<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>On Writing on Bunyk Taras</title>
    <link>http://bunyk.github.io/tags/on-writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in On Writing on Bunyk Taras</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:07:06 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bunyk.github.io/tags/on-writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Revision checklist from Technical Writing One</title>
      <link>http://bunyk.github.io/posts/revision_checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:07:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bunyk.github.io/posts/revision_checklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has nice course on technical writing. It&amp;rsquo;s text itself is example on how to apply advice you will learn there. I finished first part twice, because first time I just did exercises and not made any notes. Before starting second part I noticed that I forgot almost everything, so I retook it with also taking some notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;End of the course gives &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/tech-writing/one/summary&#34;&gt;short summary&lt;/a&gt;, but here I&amp;rsquo;ll give you mine checklist, which is a nice addition to &lt;a href=&#34;http://bunyk.github.io/posts/edx_writing/#drafting-and-revision&#34;&gt;revision checklist from Academic and Business Writing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evergreen notes</title>
      <link>http://bunyk.github.io/posts/evergreen_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 23:32:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bunyk.github.io/posts/evergreen_notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are my notes of &lt;a href=&#34;https://notes.andymatuschak.org/Evergreen_notes&#34;&gt;the notes about &amp;ldquo;evergreen notes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. I find concept interesting, as it reminds me of how I already tried to do knowledge management in the past, while editing Wikipedia, or keeping notes for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evergreen notes&lt;/strong&gt; are notes made across projects which are expected to evolve and accumulate. &amp;ldquo;Evergreen&amp;rdquo; here means functional, live &amp;amp; useful for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic and Business Writing course notes</title>
      <link>http://bunyk.github.io/posts/edx_writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 13:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bunyk.github.io/posts/edx_writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post will contain my notes and assignments from the edX course &lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.edx.org/courses/course-v1:BerkeleyX+ColWri2.2x+1T2020/course/&#34;&gt;Academic and Business Writing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would rearrange notes in order that seems more logical for the writing process, not in the order information was provided in course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general writing process could be organized in following steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading. To be a good writer you need to be active reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prewriting. All the stuff you do before you get down to actual writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing draft, trying to use correct vocabulary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revision of that draft to produce next draft with fixed writing problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeating step 4 again for more low-level improvements of text (editing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This steps and ways to get better at them will be detailed in sections below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>